准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
独角鲸来了
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
动画总监
指导总监
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
我在此以蟹堡王的名义
I hereby franchise this planet
将特许经营权授予给这座星球
in the name of the Krusty Krab
你没听到吗
Didn't you hear that?
醒醒
Wake up
小蜗  好像有别人进家里了
Gary, I think there's someone in the house
是楼下的声音
It's coming from downstairs
我好怕  可还是得下去看
I'm scared, but we got to go down there
得去
Yes
好  小蜗
Okay, Gare Bear
等我开灯
when I flip on the lights
你就朝小偷狂吠
you bark at the burglars
要用吼的  朝小偷吼出来
I mean roar, roar at the burglars
你得有残暴丛林蜗牛的样子
like the fierce jungle snail you are
娜琳
Narlene?
这不是我的老朋友小蜗吗
Well, if it ain't my old pal Gary
独角鲸娜琳
Narlene Narwhal?
自打小时候我就再也没见到过你了
I haven't seen you since we were kids
回忆的拥抱
Memory hug
珊瑚营地
看看你啊  海绵宝宝
Look at you, SpongeBob
长得老大了  还像模像样
All grown-up-ified and proper
你来看望我了
You came to visit moi?
你以前总是说
Well, you always said
要是你来到裤头村了  娜琳
"If you're ever in Bikini Bottom, Narlene
你可以跟我想住多久就住多久
you can stay with me as long as you like"
确实挺像我会说的话
Yeah, that sounds like something I'd say
可惜你弟弟诺比没跟着一起来
Too bad your little brother Nobby isn't here, too
他来了
He's here
诺比
Hey, Nobby
角摇一摇  快点进来
Shake a horn and get on in here
海绵宝宝好
Howdy, SpongeBob
哇  诺比
Wow, Nobby
你长得好大
You sure got big
我要吃东西
I need some vittles
我的冰箱就是你的冰箱  诺比
My fridge is your fridge, Nobert
那时候坐你们的车穿越森林可开心了
We had a lot of good times
riding through the woods in your wagon
我几乎都能闻到海骡子的味道了
I can almost smell the sea mule
它也记得你
He remembers you, too
抱歉  娜琳
Sorry, Narlene
我不知道你在里面
I didn't know you were in here
早安  海绵宝宝
Morning, SpongeBob
我爱死你的漩涡浴缸了
I just love your fancy whirlpool bathtub
能不能帮个忙把板刷给我
Would you be a darling and hand me a scrub brush?
谢谢
Thank you
快点
Hurry it up
别人也要用漩涡浴缸
Other people need to use the whirlpool bathtub
好
Yeah
感恩节
Thanksgiving
哒哒
Ta-da
走吧
Let's go
希望你不介意
I hope you don't mind
让咱把你家弄得特别有山间特色
that we made your house all hill-ified
山间特色
Hill-ified?
我好
Why, I'm
兴奋
thrill-ified
你好
Howdy
娜琳在吗
Is Narlene here?
是威宝表哥
It's Cousin WillyBob
威宝  这位是海绵宝宝
WillyBob, meet SpongeBob
海绵宝宝  这位是威宝
Hey, SpongeBob, meet WillyBob
娜琳的表亲都是我的表亲  威宝
Well, any cousin of Narlene's
is a cousin of mine, WillyBob
非常感谢  表亲宝宝
Well, much obliged, CousinBob
快过来  诺比
Come on, Nobby
一起摔跤
let's wrassle
好
Yeah
各位表亲  给我留点力气
Hey, cousins, save some for me
娜琳在吗
Is Narlene here?
欢迎  欢迎
Welcome, welcome
娜琳的表亲都
Any cousin of Narlene's is a--
免费住房
章鱼宝表亲
Hey, Cousin SquidBob
一起跳方块舞
let's square-dance
突发新闻
Breaking news
裤头村被独角鲸团团包围
Bikini Bottom is under siege from narwhals
拉里健身房
一大群没牙的边远山区居民大肆扰民
Toothless hoards of backwoods hill folk
达里健身房
are plaguing citizens
滑浪学校
他们坛罐乐队音乐  鬼吼鬼叫
with jug-band music, hog calling
[ 坛罐乐队：以口琴等为乐器，
以敲打坛、罐、桶等加强节奏效果的即席演奏乐队 ]
骑骡学校                山民加油站
各种语病样样皆备
and bad grammar
蟹堡王
屑嗉鱼
独角鲸大混乱
建议居民们待在室内
Citizens are advised to stay indoors
并避免随着乡间小曲的节拍跺脚
and to avoid stomping your feet
to the country-fied beat
裤头村甜蜜的家
他们来了
They's here
自己多保重
Save yourselves
你得让你亲戚走了  娜琳
I think maybe it's time to ask your kin to leave, Narlene
他们不是我亲戚
They're not my kin
我还以为是你亲戚
I thought they was your kin
我们亲戚只有威宝
WillyBob is our only relation
诺比说得对
Nobby's right
其他人根本就不是独角鲸
The rest of them ain't even narwhals
是独用鲸
They're Nearwhals
大害虫加骗人精
Phony little varmint
不管是不是亲戚
Kin or no kin
都得把这场乡间舞会五花大绑
we got to hog-tie this hoedown
好消息是
Well, the good news is
我知道有个可以帮我们忙的人
I think I know someone who can help us
坏消息是什么
What's the bad news?
海之霸
好啊
Sure
我可以帮你们除掉那些傻子独用鲸
I can get rid of those Nearwhal nimrods for you
他们的白痴家族
Their stupid family
常年跟我的白痴家族不合
has been feuding with my stupid family for years
知道了
I seen it
他们浮游生物家族确实挺会记仇
Them Planktons sure know how to hold a grudge
你好
How do?
独用鲸来了
Nearwhals
独用鲸
Nearwhals?
世仇
Feud
看吧
Voilà
抓住独用鲸
Get them Nearwhals
更宜货超市
该死的独用鲸
Consarn Nearwhals
挠他们痒痒  浮游生物家族
Give 'em the itch, Planktons
浮游生物来偷袭了
It's a plankton sneak attack
独用鲸  撤退
Nearwhals, retreat
说什么
What's that, now?
骑骡学校
舞厅
屑嗉鱼
蟹堡王
骑骡学校
滑浪学校
达里健身房
拉里健身房
好耶
Yeah
谢谢
Thank you
好耶
Yeah
有人应该要给咱亲一个
I think someone deserves a little kiss
谢谢  痞老板表亲
Thankee, Cousin Plankee
恶心
Yuck
你要多保重
Y'all take care now
我都已经在想念你们了
I already miss you guys
你们之后会早点回来看我们吗
Will you come back and visit us real soon?
比你想得还要早
Sooner than you think
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
怎么
What the--
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
记得在营地那会儿  你经常说
Remember back in camp you used to always say
要是你来城里了  娜琳
"If you're ever in town, Narlene
你随时可以跟我待一起
you can stay with me anytime"
这我没说过
I never said that
地下怪糊
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
动画总监
指导总监
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海之霸
蟹堡王
也太马虎了  尤金
Very sloppy, Eugene
留了个没防护措施的通风口
Leaving an unprotected vent
直通你办公室
that leads right into your office
完美
Perfect
秘密配方就快是我的了
The secret formula is as good as mine
成功了
I made it
好
Yes
F表示朋友  一起同甘共苦
F is for friends who do stuff together
U表示你和我
U is for you and me
快乐
N表示无论何时无论何地
N is for anywhere and anytime at all
在这蓝蓝深海里
Down here in the deep blue sea
海霸王
Bubble Bass
你在刷牙吗
Are you brushing your teeth?
在刷了  老妈
Yes, Mother
不好
Oh, no
恶心
Yuck
这地方比我大学联谊会会堂厕所还脏
This place is filthier
than the bathroom in my old fraternity house
该走了
Time to get out of here
吓死我了  头脑一片空白
Terrified, mind blank
可能还尿裤子了
possibly wetting pants
等等
Wait
我没穿裤子
I don't wear pants
运气真好
Lucky me
没错
That's right
最好给我跑
You better run
恐惧加倍了
Terror doubled
求你们了
Please
你们说啥我都照做
I'll do whatever you say
别伤害我
Just don't hurt me
我们不会伤害主上
We would never hurt the Master
等等  怎么回事
Wait, what, now?
我们在赞颂你  造物主
We are praising you, the Master Creator
我吗
Me?
对
Yes
我们是地下怪糊
We are C.H.U.M.
主上之下的大集体
Collective Hive Under Master
地下怪糊
你就是主上
You are Master
你创造了我们
You create us
都是你把海霸糊从你的上方领域
when you flush chum into sewer
冲进下水道的功劳
from your upside domain
你是说海之霸吗
You mean the Chum Bucket?
对
Yes
海霸糊与下水道的气体混合
Chum mixes with gasses in sewer
形成了我们
To form we
有道理
Makes sense
但有点傻
in a stupid sort of way
怎么回事
What's happening?
主上一定要莅临村庄
Master must come to village
让我们去敬重
so we may worship him
我喜欢让人敬重
Well, I do love to be worshiped
等等
Hold on
你怎么认得我的
How did you recognize me?
从神圣剪贴簿认出来的
From sacred scrapbook
痞老板
我们保存了
We save
一切漂下来的有关主上的文章
all articles about Master that float down here
评价
这条是评价海之霸的
Here review of Chum Bucket
他给的评分是负马桶
You get one negative toilet
尤金蟹评海之霸
绝对不要来这吃
要吃就去蟹堡王
这可能就是最高的评分了
That must be highest rating possible
对
Yep
就是最高的评价
That's the highest, all right
还是把书合上吧
Let's just close that
海霸村
主上对我们的村庄是否满意
The Master is pleased with our village?
满意
Sure
有啥不行的
Why not?
谢谢主上
Thank you, Master
谢谢
Thank you
差不多给我得了
That's enough of that
有没有纸巾什么的
Do you have a napkin or something
可以给我擦手的吗
I can use to wipe my hands off?
给主上来张纸巾
A napkin for Master
恶心
Yuck
谢谢  不过下次快一点
Thanks, but try to be a little faster next time
你们地下怪糊真的什么事都给我做吗
So you C.H.U.M. would really do anything for me?
是的
Yes, yes
主上要我们做的  我们全都照做
Whatever the Master wishes
这样就有办法了
This gives me an idea
我用不着偷偷摸摸去偷蟹黄堡秘方了
I don't need to steal
the secret Krabby Patty formula by stealth
有你们地下怪糊当靠山
With you C.H.U.M. by my side
就可以直接上蛮力了
I can take it by force
是的
Yes, yes
主上要我们做的  我们全都照做
Whatever the Master wishes
好了
All right, then
大家排好队  参加突击训练
Line up for assault training
要想成功潜入蟹堡王
In order to successfully infiltrate the Krusty Krab
就得把门砸烂
you'll need to batter some doors down
快去砸
Now get to battering
你们管那叫砸
You call that battering?
再用力点砸
Batter harder
等等
Wait
不  停
no, stop
表现如何  主上
How was that, Master?
为了让我的计划成功
In order for my plan to succeed
你们得变成神射手
you will need to be expert marksmen
大家排好队
Line up and form up
先等一下
Hold on, hold on
我先把靶子放好  然后再发射
Let me just put up these targets before you fire
主上说发射
Master say fire
我们瞄得准吗  主上
How was our aim, Master?
无懈可击
Impeccable
等最后成功进入蟹堡王了
When we finally enter the Krusty Krab
你们就会面对
you will face
一个比你们想象中还要邪恶的敌人
an enemy more evil than any of you can imagine
要想绕过老螃蟹跟他的爪牙
To get past Krabs and his vile cronies
成功偷到秘密配方
and make it to the secret formula
就要精通致人于死地的空手道
you will need to be experts in the deadly art of karate
快给主上瞧瞧你们的本事
Now show Master what you got
A+
A-plus
你们都准备好了
You're ready
蟹堡王
你好  尤金
Hello, Eugene
痞老板
Plankton?
趁我还没把你冲走  赶快滚
Get out of here before I flush you
唯一要被冲走的东西
The only thing getting flushed around here
就是你蟹黄堡秘方不会被我偷的愿望
are your hopes of the Krabby Patty formula
not being stolen by me
就你一个能拿我怎样
You and what army?
我还有地下怪糊大军能消灭你
Me and my C.H.U.M. army
痞老板  这什么疯狂玩意
Plankton, what insanity is this?
我的天才疯狂杰作
The insanity of genius
那海霸糊在干什么
What's that chum doing?
我想让它做啥就做啥
Anything I want it to
老螃蟹
Oh, Krabs
你好像有点饿的样子
You look a little hungry
给他尝尝厉害  小的们
Give him a taste, boys
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你绝对偷不到我秘方
You'll never get me formula
今天征服你秘方
Today your formula
明天征服全世界
Tomorrow the world
躲得了一时躲不了一世  老螃蟹
You can't hide forever, Krabs
快出来面对你的悲惨命运吧
Come meet your stinky fate
抱歉  老螃蟹
Sorry, Krabs
你老掉牙的杂技
Your aging acrobatics
可不是我地下怪糊的对手
are no match for my C.H.U.M. monster
再见了  白痴
So long, suckers
该死
Oh, shrimp
进攻
Attack
我的腐烂兵排
My putrescent platoon
吃木刺去吧  丑八怪
Eat splinters, ugly
这是你的最后机会  尤金
This is your last chance, Eugene
放弃秘方  否则后果自负
Give up the formula or else
什么后果
Or else what?
这个后果
Or else this
好了好了
All right, all right
秘方给你们就是了
I'll give you what you want
别伤害我就好
Just please don't hurt me
海绵宝宝  救命
SpongeBob, help
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
拦住他
Stop him
一分钱
A penny
又来了
Not again
对不起  蟹老板
I'm so sorry, Mr. Krabs
我的小英雄
My little hero
总之还是谢谢你们尽力了
Well, thanks for trying, anyway
那么
So, uh
话说回来  你们还想到上面晃晃
you guys want to hang out, you know
顺便再敬重敬重我吗
maybe worship me a little more
不  地下怪糊待在下水道里才更快乐
No, we think C.H.U.M. happier in the sewer
上面太乱了
Too crazy up here
你们还会一直敬重我的  对吧
But you'll keep worshipping me, right?
我们得看下日程表
We check our schedule
回头再说
Get back to you